Register of the Arne Swabeck Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Arne Swabeck papers,
1913-1999
87019
Swabeck, Arne
21 manuscript boxes (8.76 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, other writings, correspondence, resolutions, bulletins, minutes, pamphlets, and serial issues, relating to socialist and communist movements in the United States, and especially to the Socialist Workers Party and other Trotskyist groups in the post-World War II period.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1890 Born, Denmark
1916 Emigrates to the United States. Joins the Socialist Party and the Industrial Workers of the World
1919 Participates in Seattle General Strike
1922 Attends Fourth Congress of the Third International
1925 Elected to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the United States of America
1928 Expelled from the Communist Party, along with James Cannon and other Trotskyists
1928-1967 Participates in the American Trotskyist movement, first in the Communist League of America and then in the Socialist Workers Party
1933 Meets with Trotsky in Prinkipo, Turkey
1967 Expelled from the Socialist Workers Party
1967-1986 Continues political activity as a supporter of Maoism, participating briefly in the Progressive Labor Party
1986 Died
Scope and Content Note
Received in the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987, the papers of Arne Swabeck provide an insight into the history of American radicalism in the 20th century. Over a lifetime of political activity, Swabeck participated in such events as the 1919 Seattle General Strike and the founding of the Communist Party of the United States of America, and was involved in the American Trotskyist movement from its very beginnings. Swabeck's unpublished autobiography, which includes a chapter on his meeting with the exiled Leon Trotsky in 1933, is part of the collection (see "From Debs to Mao," 1975, in the SPEECHES AND WRITINGS series).
The Swabeck papers contain articles, theoretical writings, and speeches from the whole of his political career, tracing his evolution from trade union militant to Trotskyist activist. During his many years as a member of the Socialist Workers Party, Swabeck contributed to various Trotskyist publications, and by the late 1950s, both he and his wife identified themselves as supporters of a kind of Maoism, becoming part of a small "Pro-Chinese Tendency" within the S.W.P. Following his expulsion from the S.W.P., Swabeck continued to attempt to reconcile Trotskyism and Maoism, and was briefly a member of the Progressive Labor Party.
Swabeck conducted an extensive political correspondence, and these letters detail many of the internal debates of the American Trotskyist movement. The collection contains letters mainly from the "Pro-Chinese" phase of Swabeck's activity. The PRINTED MATTER series includes an extensive selection of Trotskyist publications, as well as some material relating to China and the New Left.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Communism--United States.; Communism.; United States--Politics and government.; Socialist Workers Party.; Fourth International.; Socialism--United States.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1956-1998. (Box 1)
  Correspondence and writings of family members, arranged within a family file, and obituary of Arne Swabeck
- Correspondence, 1946-1981. (Box 1-5)
  Letters and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1922-1977. (Box 5-12)
  Articles, autobiography, essays, lectures, and speeches, arranged chronologically by title. Includes related correspondence
- Subject File, 1957-1978. (Box 12-13)
  Articles, book excerpts, clippings, memoranda, minutes, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
- Printed Matter, 1913-1980. (Box 14-20)
  Bulletins, monographs, and serial issues, largely relating to Trotskyism, China, and the American New Left
- Photographs, 1966-1969. (Box 21)
  8 prints depicting Arne and Hilde Swabeck, and other individuals
- Phonotape, 1967. (Box 21)
  1 phonotape recording of the National Guardian China Forum, New York, 1967 March 23
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1956-1998 (Box 1)
  - Family file, 1956-1998
    - Swabeck, Edgar and Marjorie (the son and daughter-in-law of Arne Swabeck)
      - Correspondence, 1956-1992. (Folder 1: 1)
        Holographs and typescripts
      - Writings, 1959-1998. (Folder 1: 2)
    - Swabeck, Hilde (the wife of Arne Swabeck)
      - "Red China - Catalyst of World Revolution," n.d. (using the name Hilde Macleod). (Folder 1: 3)
        Typescript
      - "A Rank and File Testimony: Why I Resign from the Socialist Workers Party after 33 Years Membership," 1967. (Folder 1: 4)
  - Obituary, 1986. (Folder 1: 5)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1946-1981.
  Includes enclosures, copies of letters neither to nor from Arne Swabeck, and correspondence conducted in association with Hilde Swabeck
  - General
    - A-I (Folder 1: 6)
    - J-Z (Folder 1: 7)
  - Unidentified (Folder 1: 8)
  - Appel, Al, 1965-1972 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Barisorzi, Jack, 1965 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Boulton, Jim
    - 1960-1964 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1965-1967 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1974-1975 (Folder 2: 3)
    - 1976-1978 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Breitman, George, 1951-1981 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Britten, Joel, 1964 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Cannon, James, 1946-1970 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Charles H. Kerr Publishing Co., 1975 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Dawson, Ross, 1962 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Dobbs, Farrell, 1959-1963 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Dreiser, David, 1966 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Fiske, Helen, 1972-1976 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Frank, Pierre, 1960-1967 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Fraser, Dick and Clara, 1963-1966 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Glotzer, Albert, 1975 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Gordon, Doug and Rosemary
    - 1963 (Folder 2: 16)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
      - January-June (Folder 3: 1)
      - July-December (Folder 3: 2)
    - 1965-1967 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Graber, Henry and Mary, 1965-1971 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Healy, Gerry, 1967 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Hedlund, C. R., 1965-1966 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Hinton, William, 1967-1971 (Folder 3: 7)
  - International Socialist Review (Tom Kerry), 1963-1965 (Folder 3: 8)
  - J.R.S. Productions, Inc. (Jeremy Pikser, Carol Shaffer), 1979-1980 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Jensen, Barbara and Lars, 1974-1975 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Johnson, Charles, 1963 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Kastner, Myrtle, 1971-1972 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Klehr, Harvey, 1974-1975 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Krasnowsky, Frank
    - 1963-1970 (Folder 3: 14)
    - 1971-1972 (Folder 3: 15)
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Lennep, Joel van, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1980-1981 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Mayhew, Howard, 1961-1962 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Medlin, Virgil, 1978-1979 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Minnesota Historical Society (Michael Brook), 1971-1972 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Moltved, Georg, 1962-1967 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Monthly Review Press (Harry Braverman, Nora Lapin), 1965-1981 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Morgan, Dan, 1964-1982 (Folder 4: 8)
  - New American Movement (Ben Dobbs, Roberta Lynch), 1975-1976 (Folder 4: 9)
  - O'Connor, Harvey, 1964 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Packer, Howard
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 4: 11)
    - 1966-1972 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Pathfinder Press (Lee Evans), 1977 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Peterson, Jim, 1964 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Petras, James, 1961 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Preis, Art and Ethel, 1962-1965 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Progressive Labor Party (Milton Rosen), 1965-1968 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Revolutionary Communist League, 1974-1975 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Saling, Rick, 1972-1973 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Schanzer, Jeff, 1975 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Shannon, Brian, 1964-1965 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Shannon, John, 1977-1979 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Sinclair, Louis, 1960-1966 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Socialist Organizing Committee, 1976 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Socialist Workers Party (Farrell Dobbs, Rosemary Stone), 1959-1976 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Stamm, Thomas, 1978 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1964-1967 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Studies on the Left (Helen M. Kramer, Martin J. Sklar, James Weinstein), 1962 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Trainor, Lawrence P., 1961-1965 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Trotsky, Leon, 1933 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Wald, Alan, 1978-1980 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Walker, Mike, 1964-1965 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Warwak, Isadore, 1961-1967 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Weiss, David L., 1972-1975 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Weiss, Murry and Myrtle, 1960-1979 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Wise, Matt and Karen, 1962-1966 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Wohlforth, Tim, 1959 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Workers World Party (Sam Marcy), 1967 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Zeluck, Steve, 1964 (Folder 5: 15)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1922-1977
  - Unidentified notes, n.d. (Folder 5: 16)
    Holograph
  - "The Alliance of the Workers and Peasants under the Leadership of the Working Class in China," n.d. (Folder 5: 17)
  - "Black Gold and Imperialist Robbery in the Middle East," n.d. (Folder 5: 18)
  - "Carl Skoglund," n.d. (Folder 5: 19)
  - "China - Points from Trotskyist Movement," n.d. (Folder 5: 20)
  - "Comments on Khrushchev-Eisenhower Visits," n.d. (Folder 5: 21)
  - "The European Common Market: Toward New Prosperity or New Crisis?" n.d. (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - "In Defense of Dialectics," n.d. (Folder 6: 2)
  - Lectures on the history of the American Trotskyist movement, n.d. (Folder 6: 3)
    Holograph notes
  - "Lenin's Role," n.d. (Folder 6: 4)
  - "New Unionism in the Mines," Labor Unity, n.d. (Folder 6: 5)
    Printed copy
  - Notes on meeting with Trotsky, n.d. (Folder 6: 6)
  - "Oblique Detractors of Marxism," n.d. (Folder 6: 7)
  - "Trotsky and the Theory of Permanent Revolution," n.d. (Folder 6: 8)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Report on NAM," n.d. (Folder 6: 9)
  - "Scientific Theory and Practice in the Field of Communication," n.d. (Folder 6: 10)
  - "Some Notes for an Autobiography," n.d. (Folder 6: 11)
  - "Uninterrupted Revolution in China," n.d. (Folder 6: 12)
  - "Where We Stand," n.d. (Folder 6: 13)
  - Writing on Shanghai, n.d. (Folder 6: 14)
  - "The Building Trades Problem," Labor Herald, 1922 June. (Folder 6: 15)
  - "Building Trades Militants Organize," Labor Herald, 1923 June. (Folder 6: 16)
  - "Coal Miners in Revolt," Workers Monthly, 1925 May. (Folder 6: 17)
  - "The Makers and Masters of Steel, Workers Monthly, 1925 August. (Folder 6: 18)
  - "Organizing to Fight the Steel Trust," Workers Monthly, 1925 September. (Folder 6: 19)
  - "Report of Preliminary International Conference - International Left Opposition (Bolshevik-Leninists)," 1933 February. (Folder 6: 20)
  - "Discussions with L. D. Trotsky," 1933 March 4. (Folder 6: 21)
  - "The Decay of the Stalinist Party," New International, 1934 July. (Folder 6: 22)
  - "The Stalinists and Pacifism," New International, 1934 August. (Folder 6: 23)
  - "The A.F. of L. at the Crossroads," New International, 1934 September-October. (Folder 6: 24)
  - "The A.F. of L. at San Francisco," New International, 1934 November. (Folder 6: 25)
  - "The Second Roosevelt Election," New International, 1934 December. (Folder 6: 26)
  - "American Trade Union Problems - I," New International, 1935 January. (Folder 6: 27)
  - "American Trade Union Problems - II," New International, 1935 March. (Folder 6: 28)
  - "The New International," New International, 1935 May. (Folder 6: 29)
  - "The Passing of the N.R.A.," New International, 1935 July. (Folder 6: 30)
  - "Is a Third Party Coming?" New International, 1935 August. (Folder 6: 31)
  - "The Real Meaning of the United Front," New International, 1935 October. (Folder 6: 32)
  - "The A.F. of L. Begins to Face Issues," New International, 1935 December. (Folder 6: 33)
  - "Does the A.F. of L. Face a Split?" New International, 1936 February. (Folder 6: 34)
    Printed copy (incomplete)
  - "What Is This Business Revival?" New International, 1936 April. (Folder 6: 35)
  - "The Trade Unions in Politics," New International, 1938 March. (Folder 6: 36)
  - "Hitler's 'New Order'," Fourth International, 1941 March (pseudonym used, William F. Simmons). (Folder 6: 37)
  - "World Role of U.S. Capitalism," Fourth International, 1943 December (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 38)
  - "U. S. Capitalism Heads for Bankruptcy," Fourth International, 1944 June (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 39)
  - "Trotsky on America's Role in Europe," Fourth International, 1944 August (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 40)
  - Lectures on Marxism, 1945. (Folder 6: 41)
  - "The Outlook for a Labor Party," Fourth International, 1945 February (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 42)
  - "European Perspectives," Fourth International, 1945 April (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 43)
  - "Trotskyist Tasks in Europe," Fourth International, 1945 July (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 6: 44)
  - "Lessons of the 1919 Seattle General Strike," Fourth International, 1945 December (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - "American Imperialism at Home and Abroad," Fourth International, 1946 May (pseudonym used, William Simmons). (Folder 7: 2)
  - "The Housing Shortage," Fourth International, 1947 February. (Folder 7: 3)
  - "Rise and Decline of U.S. Capitalism," lecture, 1947 May. (Folder 7: 4)
  - "Two Pages from American Labor History," Fourth International, 1947 September-October. (Folder 7: 5)
  - "Three Years of the British Labor Government," Fourth International, 1948 March-April. (Folder 7: 6)
  - Lectures on capitalism, 1949. (Folder 7: 7)
  - "Dynamics of Revolutionary Change: A Historical Vindication," Fourth International, 1949 September. (Folder 7: 8)
  - "Some Comments on Falling Rate of Profit," Fourth International, 1949 November. (Folder 7: 9)
  - Lectures on the history of American communism, 1950. (Folder 7: 10)
  - "Crisis on Three Continents," lecture, 1950 December. (Folder 7: 11)
  - "The Method of Marxism," lecture series, 1951. (Folder 7: 12)
  - "Economic Roots of the Labor Crisis," Fourth International, 1951 March-April. (Folder 7: 13)
  - "Inflation and the Arms Economy," Fourth International, 1952 May-June. (Folder 7: 14)
  - Lecture on the history of the Communist Party of the United States of America, 1953. (Folder 7: 15)
  - Speech at banquet of the Socialist Workers Party, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1953 October 24. (Folder 7: 16)
  - "Social Relations in U.S. Today," Fourth International, 1954 Winter. (Folder 7: 17)
  - "Lessons of the Hungarian Revolution," 1956 November 30. (Folder 7: 18)
  - "American Prosperity Undermines Itself," International Socialist Review, 1957 Winter. (Folder 7: 19)
  - "The Soviet Challenge to Capitalist Economy," International Socialist Review, 1957 Spring. (Folder 7: 20)
  - "Why Beck Is Not Their Real Target," International Socialist Review, 1957 Summer. (Folder 7: 21)
  - "Lenin Memorial 1958," 1958. (Folder 7: 22)
  - "A World in Crisis," International Socialist Review, 1958 Winter. (Folder 7: 23)
  - "The 'Recession' Deepens," International Socialist Review, 1958 Spring. (Folder 7: 24)
  - "What Price Depression?" International Socialist Review, 1958 Summer. (Folder 7: 25)
  - "The Split in the AFL-CIO," International Socialist Review, 1958 Fall. (Folder 7: 26)
  - "Soviet Union and The Militant Anniversary," speech, 1958 November. (Folder 7: 27)
  - "Production, Profits and Inflation," International Socialist Review, 1959 Winter. (Folder 7: 28)
  - "Trotsky's Diary in Exile," 1959 March. (Folder 7: 29)
  - "Who Is Ahead?" International Socialist Review, 1959 Spring. (Folder 7: 30)
  - "May Day Celebration 1959," speech, 1959 May 1. (Folder 7: 31)
  - Lectures on the history of the American labor movement, 1959 November-1960 March. (Folder 7: 32)
  - "The Real Meaning of the Summit Blow-Up," 1960 June. (Folder 7: 33)
  - "The Race into Space," 1961. (Folder 7: 34)
  - "On the Post-Stalin Soviet Developments," 1962 July 31. (Folder 7: 35)
  - "In Defense of Dialectics," International Socialist Review, 1962 Fall. (Folder 7: 36)
  - "Social Relations in Cuba and Its Relations with the Soviet World," speech, 1962 October. (Folder 7: 37)
    Typescript notes
  - Banquet speech, 1962 December. (Folder 7: 38)
  - "On the Cuban Situation," 1962 December 22. (Folder 7: 39)
  - "Draft Resolution for the Party Convention," 1963. (Folder 7: 40)
  - "Idle Plants and Idle Men in a Stagnant Economy," 1963 April. (Folder 7: 41)
  - "Proposal to the Plenum," 1963 December 27. (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "The Conflict in the Fourth International and the Position of the S.W.P. on the China Question," 1964 July. (Folder 8: 2)
  - "On Khrushchev's Downfall," 1964 December 10. (Folder 8: 3)
  - Report to convention of the Socialist Workers Party, 1965. (Folder 8: 4)
  - "The Minority Position on China and Related Questions," 1965 June 1. (Folder 8: 5)
  - "Marxism, Science and Society," 1966
    - Typescript
      - Summary (Folder 8: 6)
      - Introduction (Folder 8: 7)
      - Chapter 1 (Folder 8: 8-9)
      - Chapter 2 (Folder 8: 10-11)
      - Chapter 3 (Folder 8: 12-13)
      - Chapter 4 (Folder 8: 14-17)
      - Chapter 5 (Folder 8: 18)
      - Chapter 6 (Folder 9: 4-6)
      - Chapter 7 (Folder 9: 7-9)
      - Chapter 8 (Folder 9: 10-12)
      - Chapter 9 (Folder 9: 13-15)
      - Chapter 10 (Folder 9: 16-19)
      - Chapter 11 (Folder 10: 1-2)
      - Chapter 12 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Folder 10: 4)
  - "The Socialist Cultural Revolution in China," 1966 September 22. (Folder 10: 5)
  - "An Addendum to the Socialist Cultural Revolution in China," 1966 October 22. (Folder 10: 6)
  - "Party Policy on the Chinese Revolution and in the Anti-War Movement," 1967 May 13. (Folder 10: 7)
  - Statement on being expelled from the Socialist Workers Party, 1967 July. (Folder 10: 8)
  - Writing on China, 1969 October. (Folder 10: 9)
  - "On Base Building," 1969 December 5. (Folder 10: 10)
  - "Fascism, Black Workers and Unions," 1973 November. (Folder 10: 11)
  - Article on Chinese Trotskyism, 1974 (Folder 10: 12)
  - Article on James Cannon, 1975
    - Typescript (Folder 10: 13)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Folder 10: 14)
  - "From Debs to Mao," autobiography, 1975
    - Typescript
      - Summary (Folder 10: 15)
      - Introduction (Folder 10: 16)
      - Chapter 1 (Folder 10: 17)
      - Chapter 2 (Folder 10: 18)
      - Chapter 3 (Folder 10: 19)
      - Chapter 4 (Folder 10: 20-21)
      - Chapter 5 (Folder 10: 22-23)
      - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Chapter 7 (Folder 11: 2-3)
      - Chapter 8 (Folder 11: 4-5)
      - Chapter 9 (Folder 11: 6)
      - Chapter 10 (Folder 11: 7)
      - Chapter 11 (Folder 11: 8)
      - Chapter 12 (Folder 11: 9)
      - Chapter 13 (Folder 11: 10-12)
      - Chapter 14 (Folder 11: 13-14)
      - Chapter 15 (Folder 11: 15-16)
      - Chapter 16 (Folder 11: 17-18)
      - Chapter 17 (Folder 11: 19-20)
      - Chapter 18 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
      - Chapter 19 (Folder 12: 3-4)
      - Chapter 20 (Folder 12: 5-6)
      - Chapter 21 (Folder 12: 7-8)
      - Chapter 22 (Folder 12: 9)
    - Printed copy of chapter 3, "Visiting Trotsky at Prinkipo," published in Studies in Comparative Communism, 1977 Spring-Summer (Folder 12: 10)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Article on Angolan civil war, 1976 January 16. (Folder 12: 12)
  - Article on China submitted to The Guardian (New York), 1976 December 28. (Folder 12: 13)
  - "Dialectics and the Basic Political Education Course," NAM Discussion Bulletin, 1977 Autumn. (Folder 12: 14)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1957-1978.
  Articles, book excerpts, clippings, memoranda, minutes, and reports
  - China--Politics and government
    - 1919-1949 (Folder 12: 15)
    - 1949-1976 (Folder 12: 16-17)
  - Fourth International (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Hungary--History--Revolution, 1956 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Mao, Tse-Tung (Folder 13: 3)
  - Marx, Karl (Folder 13: 4)
  - Paine, Lyman (Folder 13: 5)
  - Progressive Labor Party (Folder 13: 6)
  - Reiss, Ignace (Folder 13: 7)
  - Socialist Workers Party (Folder 13: 8)
  - Tito, Josip Broz (Folder 13: 9)
  - Trotsky, Leon (Folder 13: 10)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1913-1980. (Box 14-20)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1966-1969 (Box 21)
  - 1 print depicting unidentified group of individuals (including Arne Swabeck?), n.d. (Folder 21: 1)
  - 1 print depicting Arne and Hilde Swabeck, n.d. (Folder 21: 2)
  - 4 prints depicting Arne and Hilde Swabeck, and other individuals, 1966 (Folder 21: 3)
  - 2 prints depicting Arne Swabeck, 1969 (Folder 21: 4)
- PHONOTAPE, 1967. (Folder 21: 5)
  1 phonotape recording of the National Guardian China Forum, New York,1967 March 23.